雙 子 殺 手
比利時 列日市
六號車  我們已經出發
Car number 6, we are moving.
座位號4A  重複  座位號4A
"4 alpha", repeat, "4 alpha".
靠窗  周圍都是他的人
Window seat, his team's on all sides.
收到
Copy that.
速度是多少
Speed?
每小時238千米  勻速行進
238 km/h and holding steady.
你那邊還好嗎
You alright over there?
弄點壞蛋給我玩  我還挺開心的
I do love getting me some bad guys.
等等  停下  有平民  重複
Wait! Wait! Civilian in play, I repeat
有平民
civilian in play.
-可以射擊  -請確認
- Clear.  - Confirm.
已確認  可以射擊
Confirmed. Clear, code green.
媽的
Shit.
我們要去同一個地方嗎
Are we shipping to the same place?
是  長官
Yes, sir.
好吧
Alright.
那可是你的最好一擊
That was your best ever.
我  我真的被驚豔了
I was... I was impressed.
我擊中哪裡了
Where I hit him?
頸部
Neck.
火車可還在行進中呢
On a moving train.
-你還拍視頻了嗎  -對啊  我拍了
- You took a video?  - Yeah, I took video.
老兄  來跟大家認識認識
Man, meet everybody else, look.
-刪了  -亨利
- Delete it.  - Henry.
得了  聽著
Come on, listen.
在你接任務之前有四個槍手接連失敗
4 shooters wift on this guy before you got the call.
足足四個
Alright, 4.
都跟樁子似的
All of 'em studs.
你才是那個幹掉他的人
And you bring him off.
那場面太漂亮了
That was beautiful, alright.
我激動得眼淚都掉下來了
I got emotional, tear fell.
刪了
Delete it.
我會刪的
I'll delete it.
我到時候就刪了  好吧
I'll delete it, alright.
佐治亞州
愛莫能助
Can't do this.
怎麼樣  大哥
What's up, my brother?
你還好嗎
You alright?
我擊中了他的頸部
I got him in his neck.
但我當時瞄準的是他的腦袋
But I was aiming at his head.
別的環節出點岔子沒什麼
Other lines of work you can lose a step.
這個不行
Not this one.
你還是我們中最優秀的  同行裡最優秀的
You still the best we got. Best anyone's got.
相信我  我眼觀六路  耳聽八方
Believe me, I keep track.
不喝飲料  今天不喝
Not a soda, not today.
-啥意思  -來點啤酒
- Meaning?  - Give me a beer.
你確定嗎
Are you sure?
-你真要退休了嗎  -是  長官
- Are you really retiring?  - Yes, sir.
那我就確定要啤酒
Then I'm sure.
好嘞
Okay.
能開槍的人多了  戴爾
A lot of guys can shoot, Dell.
但是你是唯一的  你有別人沒有的經歷
They aren't you, they don't have the history you do.
我覺得  這經歷
Yeah, I think the... the history
可能也算不上什麼好事
might be the problem.
亨利
Henry.
我們一起經歷了太多  你我二人
We've been through a lot together, you and me.
讓世界變得更安全
We do world safer.
我就是沒法將對你的信任轉給新來的人
I just not gonna trust a new guy like I trust you.
當時有個小孩
There was a kid...
一個漂亮小女孩
beautiful little girl.
就在他旁邊
Right next to him.
如果我偏個15釐米
If I'm 6 inches off -
死的就是她了
she's dead.
你懂嗎
Understand?
這次
This time
是我走運
I got lucky.
我射出子彈的時候沒有那種掌控感
I didn't feel the shot.
但本來應該有的
Not like I should have.
戴爾  我殺過72個人
72 kills, Dell.
這些破事真的會影響你的
That shit starts to mess with you a little bit.
在內心深處  我感覺到
Deep down it's like...
我的靈魂好像受傷了
my soul was hurt.
我想要回歸平靜
I just want some peace.
所以  我現在該怎麼辦呢
So, what do I do now?
祝我好運吧
Wish me well.
早上好
Good morning.
傑瑞去哪了
Hey, where's Jerry?
傑瑞退休了
Jerry retired.
他們受不了他每天那麼忙了
They couldn't take anymore of his bustling pace.
我叫丹尼
I'm Danny.
你好丹尼  我是亨利
Hey Danny, I'm Henry.
我欠你23.46美元
I owe you $23.46.
好的  謝謝你  亨利
Okay, thank you, Henry.
你是為了什麼來釣魚呢
So, what are you fishing for?
平和  靜謐
Peace and quiet
還有馬鮫魚
and mackerel.
現在你要向牧師點進發了嗎
Head now to Preachers Point?
你建議我去那邊嗎
Is that what you recommend?
陽光尚好  白晝且長  何樂而不為呢
Well, seems like a nice enough day for it.
你好像不是很贊成共生共榮
Not much of a "live and let live" guy, I take it.
我對蜜蜂嚴重過敏
I'm deathly allergic to bees.
你是學生嗎  還是全職看店的
You a student or just a fish whisperer?
我還在為畢業而努力奮鬥
I'm working my way to grad school.
研究海洋生物學
Marine biology.
佐治亞大學  達裡安學院
UGA, Darian?
沖啊狗狗！
Go Dawgs!
佐治亞大學的吉祥物是鬥牛犬
你自己可要小心了
Well, you be careful around here.
碼頭那邊也有不少狗呢
There is some dogs out on these docks too.
我應付得來
Nothing I can't handle.
我猜我沒必要問你生意如何吧
Well, I guess I don't have to ask how business is.
本來應該是你的生意
Could have been yours.
也就求了你十次而已
Only asked you 10 times.
又見面了兄弟
Hey brother.
見到你可真開心啊  亨利
It's good to see you, Henry.
我也是  傑克
You too, Jack.
你在那邊都幹嘛呢  揮霍荷爾蒙嗎
What you doing there? Feeling sexy?
你這麼快就趕到我真的很感激
Thanks for coming so quickly.
應該的  你還沒離婚吧
Of course. You still married?
是啊  老婆在巴黎購物呢
Yup. Wife's on a shopping trip to Paris.
兒子上了寄宿學校
Son's in boarding school.
你呢
You?
三無  沒老婆沒娃  也去不成巴黎
No, no wife, no kids, no Paris.
敬  下一次戰爭
Here's to the next war -
-永遠不會發生  -永遠不會發生
- which is no war.  - which is no war.
你準備了什麼好東西給我
So, what've you got?
認識他嗎
Recognise him?
問這個幹什麼
Who's asking?
老朋友擔心你可能惹上麻煩了
Your old friend who's afraid you're in trouble.
你認識嗎
Do you?
我在列日市幹掉他了
I AMF'ed him in Liège.
他們告訴你他的身份了嗎
They tell you who he was?
瓦萊利·多莫夫  恐怖分子
Valery Dormov. Terrorist.
不
No.
瓦萊利·多莫夫是分子生物學家
Valery Dormov. Molecular biologist.
他在美國工作了三十年
Who worked here in the States for 30 years.
我看過他的資料
I read his file.
生化恐怖分子
Bio-terrorist.
資料被人改過了
The file was spiked.
我不知道是誰做了手腳
I don't know by who.
但是動機呢
Why?
我也無從知曉
I don't know that, either.
你是從哪知道的
Where are you getting this from?
一個朋友
A friend.
另一邊的朋友
From the other side.
好吧
Alright, well.
我要和他談談
I need to talk to him.
沒問題  電話還是視頻
Sure. Skype? Facetime?
我得和他面談  傑克
I need to talk to him, Jack.
好吧  管他呢
Oh, what a hell.
他欠我的
He owes me.
我也希望這不是真的
I hope I'm wrong.
我只是想讓你小心點
I just want you to be careful.
我要把在DIA任職時錯過的東西都補回來
It's me got full of things I didn't do in my DIA years.
DIA:美國國防情報總署
你覺得你在DIA的時候沒幹過這事嗎
You think you didn't do that in your DIA years?
這人真是
This guy.
他們告訴你他的身份了嗎
They tell you who he was?
維吉尼亞州 美國國防情報總署
瓦萊利·多莫夫  恐怖分子
Valery Dormov. Terrorist.
不
No.
瓦萊利·多莫夫是分子生物學家
Valery Dormov. Molecular biologist.
他在美國工作了三十年
Who worked here in the States for 30 years.
聯繫我真的是風險很大的事
You took a real risk contacting me.
真希望你沒聯繫我
I wish you hadn't.
我還能怎麼辦呢
What was I supposed to do?
我真愛你  兄弟
I love you, brother.
我也是
You too.
真遺憾
It's a pitty.
我一直挺喜歡亨利
I've always liked Henry.
克雷  亨利是DIA的人
Henry is DIA, Clay.
是我手下的人
He's one of mine.
他知道你騙他了
He knows you lied to him.
我們抓著他的小辮子
We have a tail on him.
退休的基本章程  我們還是控制著他
Standard protocol for retirement. He'll be contained.
誰能控制得了亨利·布洛根
Contained? Henry Brogan?
他現在知道多莫夫的聯繫方式了
He has Dormov's contact.
他會死死抓住這根稻草
He's gonna pull on that thread
一路走上前來  用槍指著我們的鼻子
until he's pointing a gun at our faces.
他的監管人呢  那個光頭
What about his handler, the bald guy?
派特森嗎
Patterson?
他肯定不高興  但他不會違抗我  沒有威脅
He won't be happy, but he won't cross me, he'll fall in line.
這事我來了結
I'll tie this off.
偽裝成俄國人的行動
Make it look like a Russian op.
這事你別插手
You'll do nothing!
我會告訴我的隊員  說亨利失控了
I'll tell my team that Henry's gone rogue.
我會處理好的
I can handle this.
在多莫夫身上你失手四次  還好意思說
Right after you wift 4 times on Dormov.
不  你需要雙子殺手
No. You need Gemini.
我絕不會允許你在美國領土上做這種事
I will not let you do hints on American soil.
你找不到能制住亨利·布洛根的人
You don't have anyone who can take on Henry Brogan.
我能
I do.
我們內部事務內部解決  謝謝你
We'll clean up our own messes, thank you.
拜您的失誤所賜
Everything that we worked for is
我們苦心經營的所有現在都岌岌可危
at stake thanks to your failures.
我只給你一次機會  你可別搞砸
You have one chance not to screw this up.
拜託你
Please.
給我點驚喜
Surprise me.
捕到什麼寶貝了嗎
Any luck?
好吧
Okay.
大多數人都會選擇送花或者
Most guys try flowers or a
放個浪漫點的歌單
playlist they think I'll find romantic.
你是DIA的人嗎
Are you DIA?
你要不要先告訴我DIA是啥
That depends what's DIA?
美國舞蹈教練協會
Dance Instructors of America.
是派特森派你來監視我的嗎
Did Patterson send you to surveil me?
哪個派特森
Patterson?
你不認識戴爾·派特森嗎
Del Patterson?
那真是巧了  他剛就在這裡
Funny coincidence, he was just here.
聽著  你完了
Look, you're burnt.
你的身份暴露了
Your cover's blown.
行吧  我剛聽
Okay, well I was just...
馬文·蓋伊的歌聽到一半
in the middle of Marvin Gaye song,
我現在要繼續了
so I'm gonna go back to that.
說出達裡安學院裡三棟建築的名稱
Name 3 buildings on a Darian Campus.
你認真的嗎
Really?
來啊海洋生物學家
Come on, marine biologist.
羅德斯樓  麥考特樓  洛克樓
Rhodes Hall, McCourter Hall, Rocker Hall.
現在我知道你就是DIA的人了
Now I know you're DIA.
平民會叫我滾開
Civilian would've told me to piss off.
有禮貌的平民不會
Not a polite civilian.
你可以啊  真挺可以的
You are good, you are good.
你住在哪
Where you live?
什麼
What?
我想看看你的住處
No, I wanna see your place.
你說什麼
Excuse me?
我肯定找不到一本
Where, I am sure I won't find a single book
海洋生物學的書
on marine biology.
但我敢肯定有一堆亨利·布洛根的情報
But I'm certain I'll find a big ol' fold on Henry Brogan.
打擾一下
Excuse me?
跟你聊的很開心  但我得做工作了
Okay, this has been fun, but I kinda have to do that job.
對不起  先生
Sorry, sir.
我有條九米的小遊艇
Yeah, I got the 30-feet bowrider.
-好的  -需要些汽油還有
- Okay. - Needs some gas and...
先生
Hey, sir.
等一下
One sec.
對不起
I'm sorry, I...
我能請你喝一杯嗎
Can I buy you a drink?
怎麼  還想繼續審問我啊
Why, so you can keep interrogating me?
不  可能我會一直朝你道歉
No, I'm probably gonna spend the whole time apologising.
鵜鶘點怎麼樣
Pelican Point?
星期天晚上他們有很棒的樂隊
Sunday nights, they have a great band.
拜託了  你幾點下班
Please, what time do you get off work?
-七點  -可能我還要一個12伏的艙底泵
- 7. - Think I also need a 12-volt bilge pump.
-12伏  -好吧  那就七點見
- 12 volt. - Alright, I'll see you at 7.
別再那麼瘋癲了
Just leave the crazy at home, please.
好吧
Alright.
之前對不起
Sorry about earlier.
壞習慣  我不那麼容易相信別人
Bad habits. I don't trust people easily.
但我肯定你也是這樣
But I'm sure you don't either.
為什麼這麼說
Why would you say that?
DIA  丹妮爾·紮卡盧夫斯基
你從哪得到的
Where did you get that?
25年忠心盡職你也會交些朋友的
25 years of faithful service you make some friends.
現在我暴露了
Now I'm burnt.
糊糊了
Toast.
是派特森在指揮你嗎
Is Patterson running you?
你們的酒
OK, here you go
-謝謝你  -不客氣
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
鍋爐工是條子的酒啊  你們家有條子嗎
Boilermaker is a cop drink. You got cops in your family?
我爸以前是FBI
My dad was FBI.
為我們國家做了不少貢獻
And pretty big on serving our country.
之前
Was?
是啊  他殉職了
Yeah, he died off duty.
為了阻止銀行搶劫案
Trying to stop a bank robbery.
很抱歉
Sorry about that.
檔案說你在巴林島海軍第五艦隊服役了四年
File says you were 4 years in Navy "Fifth Fleet", Bahrain.
是啊  挺愛大海的
Yeah, did love the sea.
但不是很喜歡跟幾百個
Didn't love being stuck on a tin can with
海員擠在一個大鐵罐裡
couple of hundreds sailors, though.
比摩加迪休的地堡要好吧
Beats a bunker in Mogadishu.
然後是DIA
So, then DIA.
國防秘密服務
Defence Clandestine Services.
招募和指揮特工
Recruiting, running assets.
沒被記過一次過
Not a single demerit.
我說
I mean...
然後檢察長派你來碼頭
So then the Inspector General sticks you on a dock
監視一個想著退休的老傢伙
to watch a guy who just wants to retire?
你也不嫌麻煩
That doesn't bother you?
這就要說再見了  亨利
Well, this is adios, Henry.
監視你很愉快
It's been nice surveilling you.
明天我就會被派去其他地方了
I'll be sent somewhere else tomorrow.
是啊
Yeah.
你要搭我車回家嗎
You... you want a ride home?
不用了  謝謝  我公寓就在那
No, thanks, my apartment is just right over there.
亨利  你為什麼要退休
Henry, why are you retiring?
我發現最近我總躲著鏡子
I'm finding myself avoiding mirrors lately, so...
我就當這是個徵兆吧
I'm gonna take that as a sign.
在外面小心點
Watch your six out there.
你也是
You too.
晚安  糊糊
Night, Toast.
過來看星星  傑克
You should come look at the stars, Jack.
-你要多練練蹬腿  -查理
- You have to work on your kick. - Charlie.
-集中注意力  亨利  -夠了
- Concentrate, Henry. - Come on!
你五歲了  這個不難
You are 5 now and this is not hard.
現在  再試一次
Now. Try again.
警告
有人侵入
這裡是傑克  出海中
Hi, this is Jack, I'm sailing.
這是不是意味著我們有生意了
Please tell me this means we're back in business.
你在哪
Where are you?
百無聊賴地監視別人
Just some goddamn surveliance.
立刻離開那
Get out of there, now!
別回家  別回你女友家
Do not go home, do not go to your girl's house.
-到車站  用現金買張票  -操
- Go to the bus station, get a ticket, in cash. - Shit.
別用取款機  去一個沒人認識你的地方
Do not use ATM. Go somewhere where nobody knows you.
你確定嗎
You sure?
有人到我窗戶外面了  抱歉我拖你下水了
They're outside my window, sorry man I made you a loose end.
沒事的  我會沒事的
Come on man, I'll be fine.
怎麼聯繫你
How do I contact with you?
別聯繫  誰也別聯繫
You don't. Don't contact anybody.
特別是DIA的人
Especially anybody from the DIA.
還有把手機扔掉  快點
And get rid of your phone. Now.
怎麼了  亨利  停下
Oh, come on, Henry. Stop.
馬里諾
Marino?
我不是來打架的
It's not gun time.
是來請你喝咖啡的
It's coffee time.
你有應急包嗎
Do you have a burn bag?
首先  告訴我你在這幹嘛
First, tell me what you're doing here.
有人派了一個小隊來殺我
Somebody just sent a team to kill me.
然後你還在睡覺
And you're still asleep.
說明你不知道  對嗎
That means you didn't know about it, correct?
當然不知道  不然我早告訴你了
No, of course not. I would've told you.
這說明你是下一個
That means you're next.
穿好衣服
Get dressed.
那些船有備用鑰匙在辦公室  對吧
All the boats have dupe keys in the office, right?
有快艇嗎
You got a fast one?
感受到海洋的呼喚了嗎
Feeling the call of the sea?
他在哪
Where is he?
你可以現在告訴我
You can tell me now.
嘿  放下
Hey, drop!
婊子
Bitch!
你是想現在說  還是想
You can tell me now, or you can
等五分鐘以後  我把你打得鼻青臉腫了再說
tell me in 5 minutes minus your teeth.
但你得告訴我
But you gonna tell me.
我聽到三聲槍響
I counted 3.
你帶了幾個人
How many did you bring?
誰派你過來的
Who sent you?
你是想現在說  還是想等五分鐘以後
You can tell me now or you can tell me in 5 minutes...
我把你打得鼻青臉腫了再說
minus your teeth.
你還好嗎
You alright?
-是萊希特  -你怎麼知道的
- It's Lassiter. - How do you know?
上了這船  你就要拋棄
You get on this boat you leave behind
你所有東西和所有認識的人
everything and everybody you've ever known.
明白嗎
Do you understand that?
害怕是好事
Scared is good.
說明你警覺起來了
It means you're alert.
還沒有人想來殺過我呢
Never had anybody trying to kill me before.
重要的是  你沒死
Yeah, well, the important thing is - you didn't.
你除了蜜蜂還害怕什麼
What scares you? Other than bees.
溺水
Drowning.
這就是你說的善後嗎
So this is you cleaning up your own messes?
別訓我了
Spare me the lecture.
就像看興登堡號撞上了泰坦尼克
It's like watching the Hindenburg crash into the Titanic.
1937年興登堡號客運飛艇空難
告訴我我們拿亨利怎麼辦
Tell me what we're going to do about Henry.
亨利·布洛根跟其他士兵一樣
Henry Brogan is like any other soldier.
年輕的時候沒腦子
When they're young and stupid
你說什麼他們都相信
they believe anything you tell them.
再老一點之後  他們
Then they get older, they
沒那麼多精力了
wear out.
長心眼了
Grow a conscious.
這也是我們需要新型士兵的原因
This is why we need a new breed of soldier.
雙子殺手可以搞定
Gemini will handle this.
對不起  我不允許
I'm sorry, I can't allow that.
我可不是在要你允許
I'm not asking your permission.
你想去找上頭嗎
You wanna go to your bosses?
他們聽到這失敗的行動肯定樂壞了
I am sure they'd love to hear about our little rogue project.
我把現場佈置成俄羅斯殺手幹的
I'll make it look like a Russian hit.
你準備給亨利舉行國葬
You give Henry a state funeral.
棺材鋪上國旗  鳴炮21響致敬
Flag on the coffin. 21-gun salute.
再準備個感人的演講  大家都哭了
You give a nice speech, everyone cries.
他會被記成英雄
He'd be remembered as a hero.
生活還得繼續
Life goes on.
-亨利卻不能了  -少來
- Not for Henry. - Oh, come on.
亨利這種人天生就是用來犧牲的
Muds like Henry look born to be collateral damage.
別假裝好人
Let's not pretend otherwise.
你有合適人選了嗎
Do you have an asset in place?
我已經有完美人選了
I have the perfect asset.
-好了  -稍微
- Alright - Just...
我沒事了
No, I'm good.
你餓嗎
You hungry?
我餓死了  但那玩意三年前就過期了
Yeah, I'm starving, but those things expired 3 years ago.
真的嗎
Really?
還很好吃呢
Still taste good.
那傢伙嘴裡還有牙的時候說你叛變了
While he still had teeth that guy said you were the rogue.
你相信他了嗎
And you believed him?
他百分之99在說謊
99% sure he was lying.
但百分之一也難受啊  對吧
But 1% sucks, doesn't it?
亨利  你之前碰到過這種事嗎
Henry, has this ever happened to you before?
那一部分
Which part?
你自己的政府想來殺你
Your own government trying to kill you.
沒碰到過
Nah, that's new.
你在局裡這麼長時間
You've been in agency a while and
都猜不到這是怎麼了嗎
can't you guess what this is all about?
相信我  我要是能猜到
Trust me, if I could I would not be
就不會跟你在這度假了
on this lovely vacation with you.
等我當上局長
When I'm the head of the agency we
一定把退休機制全改了
gonna handle retirement very differently.
我哥們
My man.
巴倫旅遊來接布洛根
Baron tour is here to pick up Brogan.
兩位旅客
Party of two.
-很高興見到你  -你也是
- Good to see you man. - You too.
丹尼  這是巴倫
Danny, meet the Baron.
中年無賴  我認識的最棒的飛行員
Middle-aged reprobate and best pilot I've ever known.
丹尼  巴倫
Danny, Baron.
你好  糊糊
Hey, Toast.
你要的裝備都準備好了
Got your appliences requested.
你們可以先去我那裡呆一陣  在喀他赫納
For now, you can hold up to my place at Cartagena.
沒有人認識你  很安全
You'll be anonymous and safe.
是啊  我們現在水深火熱呢
Yeah, we're kinda in the shit here, man.
我覺得傑克已經死了
I think Jack is dead.
-天哪  -是啊
- Jesus. - Yeah.
-有人跟蹤你們嗎  -沒有
- Anyone follow you? - No.
會跟來的  出發吧
They will. Let's go.
-我能吃一片餅乾嗎  -當然
- Can I have one of those crackers? - Sure.
謝謝
Thanks.
他在家也這麼做嗎
Does he do this at home?
我不覺得  我不知道
I don't think so, I don't know.
-你會嗎  -當然不
- Do you? - No.
如果在家做這種事不像話
If it's inappropriate to do this sort of thing at home.
你覺得在科學課上
Why would you think it's appropriate
做這種事像話嗎
to do it in your science class?
我不知道  大概因為理科太無聊了
I don't know, probably because science is so wicked boring.
你好
Hello.
我想你大概也不希望我退休
Guess you really didn't want me to retire.
亨利  你還好  謝天謝地
Henry, you're okay! Thank God!
省省吧
Stop it!
馬里諾死了嗎
Is Marino dead?
是的
Yes.
傑克·威利斯呢
Jack Willis?
不是我幹的  都不是我幹的
It wasn't me. None of this was me
亨利  我發誓
Henry, I swear it.
我相信過你  戴爾
I trusted you, Dell.
你可以繼續相信  我換個手機給你打電話
You still can. Let me call you on another line.
604 555 0131
我給你30秒
You got 30 seconds.
抱歉
Hey, excuse me.
我能借你手機5分鐘時間嗎
Could you borrow a phone for 5 minutes
我給你100美金
if I gave you a hundred bucks?
我們先談談是誰想到的
We'll start with who's idea it was to send a team
派支小隊去紮卡維斯基探員家裡  有必要嗎
to agent Zakarweski's apartment, was that necessary?
也不是我的決定
Also not my call, she's working
她在為督察長工作  不是我
for the Inspector General, not me.
她和你在一起嗎
Is she with you?
是的
Yes.
不是自願的吧
Not voluntarily.
好了聽著  我不想在電話上說這事
Okay, listen, this is not something I wanna say over the phone.
我他媽現在在我孩子的學校
I'm at my kids, goddamn, school!
這他媽都是什麼事
What a hell is all of this?!
我們出了點問題
We have a problem.
雙子殺手
Gemini.
你的老朋友  在和珍內特·萊希特的人合作
Your old friend, working with Janet Lassiter and her people.
我沒法阻止他們
I can't stop them.
好的  多莫夫
Okay, Dormov.
他和雙子殺手有關係嗎
Did he have something to do with Gemini?
多莫夫  你讓我在火車上殺的那個
Dormov, the guy that you had me popped on the train.
因為你說他是俄羅斯恐怖分子
Because you said he was a Russian terrorist.
他在為雙子殺手工作嗎
Was he working for Gemini?
以前是
Once upon a time.
所以你讓我給克雷·維裡斯挑的頭
So you got me pulling triggers for Clay Verris.
亨利  我很後悔沒對你坦誠相待  但聽好
Henry, I regret my lack of candor, but listen...
你有多少次這樣對我了  戴爾
How many other times you do this to me, Dell?
有多少次你改了檔
How many times you spiked a file,
讓我把不該死的人送上西天
send me off to AMF somebody who didn't deserve it?
從來沒有  就這麼一次
Never, ever. This was the one-off.
我以我兒子的性命發誓
I swear on my son's life.
好吧  聽著
Alright, look.
紮卡維斯基探員和這事無關
Agent Zakarweski is not a part of this.
亨利  我們能行  我發誓
Henry, we can fix this. I swear, but I need
但我需要你們倆一起回來
both of you to come back.
回哪裡  戴爾
To what, Dell?
好吧  雙子殺手
Okay, Gemini.
你對他瞭解多少
What do you know about it?
克雷·維裡斯擁有的私營准軍事團隊
Privatized paramilitary owned by Clay Verris.
局裡和他們在業務上有很多往來
Agency does a lot of business with them.
還有呢
Is there more?
巴倫和我在海軍裡在維裡斯手下
Baron and I served under Verris in the Marines:
去過巴拿馬  科威特  索馬里
in Panama, Kuwait, Somalia.
之後他就離開了軍隊
After he left the military, he started
他建立了雙子殺手  想雇我們
Gemini and tried to hire us.
我們都拒絕他了
We both told him "no".
我學聰明了  搬家去了2400公里外的地方
Except I was smart enough to move 1500 miles away.
是啊
Yeah.
我搞砸了
I blowed that one.
哥倫比亞  卡塔赫納
歡迎來到哥倫比亞
維裡斯靠各種手段幹掉目標
Verris gets billions of dollars a year to take
一年能賺幾十億美元
out targets in any way he sees fit.
這就是雙子殺手
That's Gemini:
私下綁架  拷問
off-book kidnappings, tortures.
你想讓12個沙特王子悄悄消失的話
They who you call when you need 12 Saudi princes
找他們就對了
to quietly disappear.
或者你想找人訓練你的敢死隊
Or you want somebody to train your death squads.
我上狙擊學校六周之後
6 weeks into Sniper School
克雷·維裡斯帶我出海八公里
Clay Verris takes me out on this boat for 5 miles.
在我腳踝上綁上負重  把我扔到海裡
Ties this weights to my ankles, tosses me overboard.
叫我盡可能久地踩水
Tells me tread water as long as I can.
他不知道你怕
And he didn't know about your fear of...
他當然知道  這就是他的目的
Of course did. That was the point.
那你怎麼辦呢
So what did you do?
我盡可能久地踩水
I tread water for as long as I could.
然後淹死了
And then I drowned.
死了
Dead.
他把我撈出來  拍拍我的胸口
He fished me out, pat on my chest.
告訴我我現在夠格做他的手下了
Told me I was now ready to serve under his command.
乾杯
A toast.
敬下一次戰爭
To the next war...
-永遠不會發生  -永遠不會發生
- which is no war. - which is no war.
沒有戰爭
No war.
我們明早再商量
We'll figure out in the morning.
現在需要先歇一歇
Right now we can use some shelter.
當然  你們想要一間房還是
Sure, you folks want one room or...
兩間
Two.
兩間  兩間
Two, two.
好啊  如果你想的話我還能把他塞去車庫
Yeah, I can put him in the garage if you want.
好了  那就兩間房
Alright, two rooms will be fine.
就給你們個選擇  這裡走
Just giving you options. Okay, right this way.
樓頂有狙擊手  我去引開他
Sniper, rooftop, I leave, he's gonna follow.
你和巴倫一起去安全的地方
I need you to go with Baron some place safe.
好嗎
Alright?
狙擊手  在樓頂
Shooter, on the roof.
你真是個糟糕的房客  你知道嗎
You are a shitty house guest, you know that?
他們怎麼找到我們的
How the hell did they find us?
她是好人  真的是好人
She's good, she's really good.
她只是不知道自己被人利用了
She just doesn't know what she doesn't know.
照顧好她  好嗎
Take care of her, alright?
停下別動
Stop right there!
你是誰
Who are you?
我不想對你開槍
I don't wanna shoot you!
好啊
Fine.
別對我開槍
Don't shoot me.
那我對你開槍好嗎
Mind if I shoot you?
你剛剛在樓頂上我就能殺了你
I could have killed you on the roof.
也許你那時應該殺了我
Maybe you should have.
他們是給你看過我的照片嗎
Did they show you a picture of me?
是啊  你看起來真老
Yeah, you look old.
小鬼  你要是再靠近一步
Kid, you take one step closer.
我就別無選擇了
You gonna leave me no choice.
鬆手  鬆手
Get off! Get off!
閃開  閃開
Move, move!
別擋我路
Get out of the way!
停下  停下  停下
Stop. Stop. Stop!
舉起手來
Hands up!
剛剛是什麼鬼
What the hell was that?
國 家 警 察 局
布洛根
Brogan.
謝謝你  警官
Thank you, sir.
-謝謝你  隊長  -不客氣
- Thank you, Captain. - No problem.
你那邊已經暴露了
Your place is burnt,
給我找個視野開闊的地方
give me somewhere I can see him coming.
我本來想拿槍進去救你的
I wanted to go in there guns blazing.
但她覺得外交手段更好
But she thought that diplomatic approach made more sense.
是啊  開火可能反而更好
Yeah, gunfire might have been kinder.
幹得不錯
Great work in there.
現在呢
What now?
帶我去布達佩斯
I need you to get me to Budapest.
-為什麼去布達佩斯  -為什麼去布達佩斯
- What's in Budapest? - What's in Budapest?
傑克的線人  尤裡
Jack's informant Yuri.
他們不是因為我想退休所以追殺我
These guys aren't trying to kill me because I wanna retire.
他們追殺我是因為
They're coming after me because they
他們覺得傑克告訴了我機密資訊
think Jack told me something classified.
尤裡應該知道這事
Yuri ought to know about it.
抱歉兄弟  但我的阿茲特克
I'm sorry, partner, but my Aztec
飛不了這麼遠
doesn't have that kind of voyage.
那我希望能借一架能飛過去的
Well, I was hoping we would borrow something that does.
比如G系
Maybe a G?
要借一架灣流嗎
Taking someone's Gulfstream?
你得多愛一個人才肯把灣流借給他
I mean you.. you'd really have to love the guy to do that.
我正好知道有個人  等我一會兒
I know just the fellow. Give me a minute.
♪ 我在小鎮那頭  有個馬子 ♪
♪ Well, I got a woman, way over town ♪
♪ 她對我很好 ♪
♪ That's good to me, oh yeah ♪
♪ 我在小鎮那頭  有個馬子 ♪
♪ I got a woman, way over town ♪
♪ 對我很好 ♪
♪ Good to me, oh yeah ♪
♪ 我要錢  她就會給我 ♪
♪ She give me money when I'm in need ♪
亨利
Henry?
你有過小孩嗎
Did you ever have a kid?
沒有  怎麼了
No, why?
那個摩托男
Guy on a motorcycle.
你注意到什麼了嗎
Did you notice anything funny about him?
我注意到他特別厲害
I noticed he was very good.
沒錯
Right.
那臉呢
And the face?
有點熟悉嗎
Similarity?
是啊  我也注意到了
Yeah, I noticed that too.
那麼
So...
你有過長期的親密關係嗎
You never had a long-term relationship?
沒有
No.
除非把你算上
Unless we count you.
有沒有可能你有個小孩  但你不知道
Is it possible that you could've had kid without knowing it?
不可能
No.
-那你怎麼解釋  -丹尼
- Then how do you explain... - Danny.
別問了
Alright?
順便  謝謝
Thank you, by the way.
謝什麼
For?
謝謝你離開了巴倫的公寓
For leaving Baron's appartment,
我就不是他們的目標了
so I wouldn't be a target.
來佐治亞州救我
Coming and getting me in Georgia
那時你明明可以一走了之
when you could've just ran for you life.
我只是
I just...
想讓你坐私人飛機
wanted to put you on a private plane
去匈牙利免費旅遊一次
and give you a free trip to Hungary.
我在那兒能看到
Where I am gonna find...?
匈牙利人
"Hungarians".
沒錯
Right.
我看到他時
When I saw him.
就像看到鬼了一樣
It was like I was seeing a ghost.
拿著槍的鬼
Ghost with a gun.
就像
Like...
死在我搶下的每一個鬼
every trigger I've ever pulled.
佐治亞州  葛籣維爾
我告訴過你在哥倫比亞待命
I told you to stay in Colombia and wait for orders.
我想和你談談
I wanted to talk to you.
他很厲害
He is very good.
他是最厲害的
He's the best.
所以我派你去
That's why I sent you.
我每一步行動前他都能知道
He knew every move of mine before I made it.
我本可以拿下他  就在那兒  扣下扳機
I'd have him, right there, and... take the shot
然後
and...
他就死了
he'd be gone.
像鬼一樣
Like a ghost.
你看到他的臉了嗎
Did you get a look at his face?
沒看清  我在臺階的髒鏡子裡看到了
Not really, I saw him at the stairs through a dirty mirror.
我以為你在樓頂上
I thought you were on the roof.
我開始是的  他瞄準我了  我得下去
I was, he got a line on me, I had to jump down.
我們是怎麼演習的
What do we always drill?
佔領高地  把他逼向絕路
You hold the high ground, you put his back against the wall
不能讓他逃跑
and you don't let him go.
我知道
I know that.
整件事就很怪
Whole thing was weird.
就是
Just...
詭異
wicky.
怎麼怪了
How?
我不知道  就是
I don't know, it was...
就好像我游離在
As if I were...
身體之外看著一樣
watching it all.
他是誰
Who is he?
孩子  困擾著你的
Junior, this thing, that you
這件事情  這種陌生感
are struggling with, this strangeness.
是恐懼
It's fear.
不要厭惡它
Don't hate it -
要依靠它
lean into it.
擁抱它
Embraced it.
最終克服它
And then overcome it.
只要你能跨過這道門檻  孩子
You, are right in the threshold, son.
就是這樣
This cause.
你餓嗎
You hungry?
是的  長官
Yes, sir.
來碗甜麥片嗎
Bowl of cereals hungry?
好的  長官
Yes, sir.
訓 練 完 成
謝謝  訓練完畢  舉起手來
Thank you. That's it. Hands up.
過來  所有人排隊
Over here, everyboy take the line.
都歸隊
Everybody back to one.
好了  出發
That's one, let's go!
來了許多新面孔  是啊
Lots of new faces. Yeap.
他們會是第一批被派到葉門的
They'll be the first boots on the ground in Yemen.
他們知道作戰規則嗎  還是
Do they understand the rules of engagement, or, just...
只要看到動的東西就開槍
whatever moves - they shoot it?
他們是精英  訓練有素
They are elite, they're disciplined.
如果他們能夠通過公寓窗戶
And if they get a clean shot at their
精准迅速地擊中目標
target through an appartment window
他們就會出手
they'll take it.
你應該在去布達佩斯的路上好好想想
You should think about that on your way to Budapest.
亨利剛在那邊落地
Henry's just landed there.
你動身吧
You're moving out.
匈牙利  布達佩斯
阿妮科
Aniko?
謝謝你為我服務
Thank you for your time.
這是樣本
Here are the samples.
結果至少得等到
Least I can do for you in...
2天后
2 days.
我2小時後就要
This I need in 2 hours.
我們約到了尤裡
We have a meeting with Yuri.
他同意跟我們會面了
He agreed to sit with us.
你還好嗎
You alright?
我想我已經知道了為什麼他和你那麼像了  亨利
I think I know why is he as good as you, Henry.
他就是你
He is you.
你說什麼
What?
這裡有個基因檢測站  我去找了他們
There's a DNA lab here, I gave them samples.
化驗了你的  還有他棒球帽上的樣本
Yours and the baseball cap he was wearing.
他真的和你長得太像了
He just, he looks so much like you.
我想他可能是你的兒子  所以我才
I thought he had to be your son, so I...
他們化驗了3次
They did 3 tests.
檢測你和他的基因
Your DNA and his.
3次的化驗結果都是一致的
All 3 came back identical.
不是相近  是一致
Not close, identical.
也就是說  你們是同一個人
As in, same person.
他是你的克隆
He's your clone.
我想過我是不是錯把兩份
I thought I've made a mistake that I
同一個人的樣本給了他們
gave them two samples of the same person.
但是我沒有
But I didn't.
他就是你
He is you.
這怎麼可能呢
How's that even possible?
這很複雜  不過是有可能的
It's complicated, but it's doable.
只需要有一個代孕母親和一份基因樣本
All you'd really need is a surrogate mother and a DNA sample.
如果他們可以克隆人的話
If they could clone a person.
他們怎麼不去多克隆一些
You'd think that they'd clone more
醫生或者科學家  而是克隆
doctors or scientists, not...
我
me.
他們應該克隆納爾遜·曼德拉
They could've cloned Nelson Mandela.
納爾遜·曼德拉做不到從兩公里外
Nelson Mandela couldn't kill a man
殺死一個在行駛中的火車上的人
on a moving train from 2 kilometers away.
尤裡
Yuri?
布洛根先生
Mr. Brogan?
開始之前  我必須承認
Before we begin, I must confess.
我多年來一直都很欽佩您的工作
I have admired your work for many years.
等等  所以你知道我是誰
Wait. So you know who I am?
用你們的話來說就是
"Long time listener, first time caller", -
久聞大名  今日得見
as they say in your country.
我本應該恭喜你
I would congratulate you
光榮退休  但是
on your retirement, but...
你最後一次任務
your last job has...
並不順利  是嗎
loose ends, yes?
是啊  我的政府不僅騙了我  還打算殺掉我
Yeah, well... My government lied to me and then tried to kill me.
你是指這個吧
If that's what you mean.
是的
Yes.
在俄羅斯  這就是家常便飯
In Russia, you call that "Tuesday".
但美國人會覺得很受傷
But Americans, it hurts your feelings.
所以呢
So.
所以多莫夫為什麼要回俄羅斯
So, why was Dormov trying to go back to Russia?
為什麼派我去殺掉他
And why was I sent to kill him?
開門見山
Yeah, down to business.
果然是美國作風
Very American.
你是個大忙人
You are a busy man.
我們都是傑克的朋友
We were both friends with Jack.
他是個很好的人
He was a good man.
我和你一樣悼念他的死亡
I mourn his death, like you.
但你現在還能來到這裡
But the reason you are here
並且我目前還沒有
and I have not killed you
殺掉你
yet.
是因為我們有著共同的敵人
Is we share a common enemy.
克雷·維裡斯
Clay Verris.
他把多莫夫引到西方去  投資他的實驗室
He lured Dormov to the west, funded his lab.
你已經領教過他們的成果了吧
And now you have met the fruits of their labor.
多莉羊是1996年被克隆的
Dolly the Sheep was cloned in '96.
-但在1995年  -我就是那只羊
- But in '95... - I was the sheep.
把它當作一種榮譽吧
Take it as a compliment.
你可是獨一無二的
And you're the only one.
他用你的基因培育那個男孩成為他的孩子
With your DNA Verris raised the boy as his son.
訓練他成為最完美的殺手
Trained him to be the perfect assassin.
那多莫夫為什麼要離開
So why was Dormov trying to leave?
一直以來我們都想引他回來
For years, we tried to lure him back.
但沒有成功
Nothing.
直到去年他們出現了分歧
Then last year they had a fallen out.
多莫夫害怕了  就來聯繫我
Dormov got scared, reached out to me.
所以我
So I...
這還是解釋不了為什麼我被派去殺他
That still doesn't explain why I was sent to kill him.
我們有跡象表明多莫夫取得了突破
We have indications Dormov made a breakthrough.
人類基因改造
Modified human DNA.
還能投入大規模生產
A path to mass produciton.
多莫夫希望能提高士兵的體力和智力
But Dormov wanted soldiers to be stroger, smarter.
而維裡斯
Verris...
他想要別的東西
Verris wanted something else.
他想要什麼
What something else?
布洛根先生
Mr. Brogan.
儘管你已經是最好的殺手
You are the best at what you do.
但還是會感到分身乏術
But still you get tired,
你也有恐懼  疑慮
you have fears, doubts,
會感到痛苦甚至悔恨
you feel pain, perhaps remorse.
你有良知
You have a conscience.
這些讓你成為了一個人類
These makes you human.
但不能讓你成為最理想的戰士
But sub-optimital as a soldier.
不夠完美
Less than perfect.
利潤就會降低
Less profitable.
克雷頓 維裡斯想利用基因逆天而行
Clayton Verris is playing God with DNA.
他必須被阻止
He must be stopped.
如果他這麼危險  為什麼你不直接發射導彈
If he's that dangerous why don't you send a missile?
炸了他的實驗室
Blow up his lab.
我們正是要這樣做
That is what we're doing.
只不過
Except...
你
you
就是那枚導彈
are the missile.
祝你好運
I wish you luck.
還有一件事
One last thing.
你兩天前從家裡逃出來了
You escaped from home two days ago?
該死
Shit.
真是太精彩了
Amazing work.
我當時真是替你捏了把汗
I was on the edge of my seat.
等等  什麼
Wait, what?
你他媽是怎麼知道的
How the hell you know about that?
我可是你的超級粉絲啊
I'm a big fan, what can I say?
如果他說的話有一半是真的
If even half of what he's saying is true.
我們就得跟這個孩子聊聊
We gotta talk to this kid.
不然在此之前你都處於危險之中
You're not gonna be safe until you do.
你覺得如果一個50歲的你出現在你面前跟你說
So you think if your 50-year old self showed up and told you
你是她的克隆  你能冷靜下來嗎
you're her clone that would make you calmer?
51歲
51.
-什麼  -就是提醒你一下
- What? - Just saying, you're...
-你知道你已經51歲了吧  -已經知道了
-You know you're 51, yeah? - I rounded.
他是一面你不願意照的鏡子  亨利
He's the mirror you don't want to look into, Henry.
但他是我們找到維裡斯最好的機會
But he's our best shot in getting to Verris.
珍內特·萊希特
Janet Lassiter?
誰找我
Who wants to know?
我給您傳個信  女士
I got a message for you, ma'am.
有個人給我的羽毛幣帳戶轉了1000美元
From a man who transferred a $1000 into my Featherquin account
讓我務必傳信給你
just to make sure you got it.
那個人叫什麼名字
Does this person have a name?
他叫  匯1000美元到我的羽毛幣帳戶
His name is "$1000 into my Featherquin account".
你好  珍內特
Hello, Janet.
在你試圖又一次殺掉我之前  好好考慮
Before you try to kill me again, consider this.
你的家庭地址是卡羅爾·格羅夫街1362號
Your home address is 1362, Carol Grove.
安全警報密碼是1776
The security alarm code is 1776.
你每天早上6點12分起床
You awaken at 6:12 every morning.
在6點42分前喝一杯無咖啡因的拿鐵咖啡
and stop for your decaf soy latte with an extra shot by 6:42.
每晚你都會站在客廳的大窗戶前面
Every night you stand in front of your huge living room window,
一邊喝著豪帥快活的瑪格麗塔酒
sipping a Jose Cuervo Margarita
一邊看電視上的《法醫檔案》
with Forensic Files on the TV.
穿著你高級舒適的運動褲
Wearing your nice, comfy sweatpants.
我是萊希特
This is Lassiter.
在你10點和2點方向都有搶手
There are shooters at your 10 and 2.
一旦離開這個椅子  就會立刻喪命
Get above of that chair, you will be AMF'ed.
如果我認為世界上還需要有另外一個我的話
Now, if I thought the world needed another me
我會生個孩子
I would've had a kid.
這個項目在我來之前已經啟動了
The program predates my arrival at the agency,
你知道這一點
You must know that.
是的  真是標準的華盛頓式回答
Yeah, perfect DC answer.
出現問題只會開溜
If something goes wrong - duck.
給那個騎自行車的小子一點小費
Tip the bike guy.
你可以走了
You can go.
聽著  我挾持了一名你的探員
Now, I have your agent with me against her will.
丹妮爾·紮卡維斯基
Danielle Zakarweski.
她想加入
She wants to come in.
行
Fine.
她和我一樣  是個愛國者
Now, like me, she is a patriot.
不同的是
Unlike me,
她仍然想要在未來的幾十年裡
she still wants to spend the next couple decades
為你們這些混蛋衝鋒陷陣
scoring touchdowns for you assholes.
她的安全必須要得到保證
Her safety is non-negotiable.
10點和2點方向  珍內特
10 and 2, Janet.
珍內特點的另一杯無咖啡因拿鐵咖啡
Decaf soy latte, an extra shot for Janet?
我只會把她交給一個人
The only person I'll turn her over to
就是在卡塔赫納你派來追殺我的那個
is the guy you sent after me in Cartagena.
派其他人來的這個念頭想都別想
Don't even think about sending anybody else.
家人團聚  很甜蜜
Family reunion, very sweet.
是
Yeah.
你最好把你該做的事做了
Keep it up,
否則  你就是我第一次無償殺人的小白鼠
you'll be the first person I've ever killed for free.
你多快能把他送到布達佩斯
How quickly can you get him to Budapest?
5分鐘
5 minutes.
很好
Good.
她今晚午夜會在
She'll be in the courtyard of the
瓦伊達洪城堡的院子等你
Vajdahunyad Castle at midnight, tonight.
慢慢享用你的拿鐵吧
Enjoy your latte.
AMF是什麼意思
What's AMF?
再您媽的見
Adios mother fucker.
他是怎麼知道我們在這兒的
How the hell does he know we're here?
這樣會有用嗎
This is gonna work, right?
會的
Yes.
你怎麼知道
How do you know?
我還不知道他的喜好嗎
I know his taste.
等等  你的意思是你對我有興趣嗎
Wait, are you saying you are attracted to me?
我嗎
Me?
現在的我嗎  怎麼可能
Now? Hell no.
不過那個年輕稚嫩版本的我或許會考慮下
But the younger, less mature version, maybe.
我在佐治亞州找你的時候
When I came for you in Georgia,
我完全是沒經過大腦思考的  是一種直覺
I didn't have to think about that, it was instinct.
所以他也一樣會有這種本能
He was born with that too.
況且  他想要的是我
Besides, he wants me.
右轉
Right.
院子挺漂亮
Lovely courtyard.
抱歉  女士
I'm sorry, ma'am.
在進行下一步前  我需要你卸下所有衣物
Before we go any further, I'm gonna need you to strip.
你再說一遍
I beg you pardon?
我必須要確認你身上沒有任何設備
Need to be certain you're not wearing a wire.
好吧  首先
Okay, first of all.
"女士"是什麼意思
Ma'am?
我從小就被教導要尊重長輩
I was raised to respect my elders.
請脫下你的衣服
Take off your clothes, please.
請轉一下身
Turn around, please.
看來你很嚴謹啊
I see you like to be thorough?
唯有警惕讓我得以生存下去
Caution is kept me alive.
打給這個一次性手機
Call this burner.
謝謝
Thank you.
布洛根
Brogan.
你有12分鐘
In 12 minutes,
不然我就讓她腦殼裡多兩顆子彈
I'm putting 2 bullets in the back of her head.
你的指令是把她安全地送過去
Your orders are to deliver her safely.
我的指令是殺了你
My orders are to kill you.
你熟悉地下墓穴的石英室嗎
Are you familiar with the quartz chamber at the catacombs?
不行
Negative.
必須得在顯眼的地方  我要能看到你
We're doing it someplace visible, where I can see you.
你還有11分鐘
Now you have 11 minutes.
把衣服穿好  我們要坐車走了
Get dressed. We're taking a ride.
計程車  不錯的選擇
Cab was a smart move.
你是哪兒人
Where are you from?
這麼有禮節  是南方人吧
Your formality, it's Southern.
你要是想把我當成誘餌
You know if you gonna use me as bait
並且最後可能殺了我的話
and possible murder me
那你至少也應該和我說說話減輕我的壓力
then the least you can do is indulge me in some conversation.
就在亞特蘭大附近
Just outside Atlanta.
你們兩個很像呢
You two have a lot in common.
這我不太信
I doubt that.
你會驚訝的
You'd be surprised.
我一開始也是這麼跟著他
You know I started following him too
就像你一樣
just like you're doing.
後來我對他有了更深入的瞭解
Then I got to know him.
他和你一樣  有一顆寬容的心
He's got a big heart, like you.
你又怎麼知道我的心怎麼了
What do you know about my heart?
反正我知道你有那麼一顆心
I know that you have one.
我還知道你的心在告訴你
And I know that it's telling you that something
說你的肩負的工作總有些不對勁
about the job you've been given isn't right.
工作就是工作  女士
Job is the job, ma'am.
真好奇你給這兒的管理員塞了多少錢
I wonder how much you payed the custodian.
左轉
Left.
把鏈條打開
Undo the chain.
地下室啊
Basement.
看來你很瞭解這座城市啊
You must really know the city.
我經常看國家地理
I watch a lot of Nat Geo.
-這兒寫著"越界"  -請吧
- It says "Off limits". - Ma'am.
不知道有多少人被埋葬在這裡呢
I wonder how many people are buried down here.
站到那邊去
Stand over there.
走
Go.
你要是把燈全給打壞了
If you knock out all the lights,
你待會出去的時候怎麼看得清你的陷阱呢
how are you gonna see your own tripwire on the way out?
炸彈可不是開玩笑的  我知道是怎麼回事
The granade is no joke, I mean I get the idea.
黑暗能削弱他的力量
Darkness neutralizes his biggest strength,
讓他成為你的甕中之鼈  對吧
enclosed court favors you, right?
但他要是扔炸彈  肯定會把我也誤殺了的
I mean he can't throw a grenade without killing me too.
但我要是用氣體來對付你呢
But what if I tries gas?
你懂的  包含點兒鎮靜劑的那種
You know, or some sort of sedative agent?
你還真是想得遠多過我
Way ahead of me.
防毒面具加夜視眼鏡  很聰明
Gas mask and night vision, very smart.
-到那兒去  -鏈條哎
- Over there. - Zip ties!
是給我準備的吧
These must be for me?
我能再問你一個問題嗎
But can I ask you something?
你有停下來給我回答的時間嗎
Would you actually stop talking long enough for me to answer?
你有多瞭解他
How much do you know about him?
或者  他們有告訴你他們想殺他的原因嗎
I mean, would they tell you why they wanted him dead?
是這傢伙瘋了
Guy cracked.
一晚上殺了八個特工  包括蹲他的眼線
Killed 8 ops in a single night and his spotter.
-這只是他們告訴你的  -這就是他做的事
- That's what they told you? - That's what he did.
不
No.
不  不完全是
No, not exactly.
我當時也在
I was there.
那晚  所有的特工都被打了
The night all those operatives were hit.
他們被下令去殺他
They'd been sent to kill him,
還有我  都是雙子殺手指使的
and me, by Gemini.
還有  他的眼線是在維吉尼亞州被射殺的
And not that it matters, but his spotter were shot in Virginia
而剩下的那些人則是在薩凡納被打死的
and the rest of those men went down in Savannah.
亨利是能狙擊  但他也狙不了那麼遠
Henry can shoot long distance, but he can't shoot that long.
拜託你想想  你不覺得這樣很沒邏輯嗎
Come on, just think. Does that make any sense to you?
你明白我在說什麼嗎  這不
So you understand what I'm saying? It doesn't...
清靜多了
Better.
操你媽
Fuck you.
起來  走
Get up. Go.
待在那兒別動
Stay right there.
-謝謝  -小意思
- Thank you. - Yeah.
你知道怎麼把那玩意兒點起來嗎
Do you know how to light one of those?
老天呐  亨利
Jesus, Henry.
謝謝你提醒了炸彈的事情
Thanks for the tip on the granade.
你一直在和他說話
You were talking to him all the time?
沒錯
Yeah.
你要麼搜身
You either search somebody.
要麼不搜
Or you don't.
我先警告你一句
And for the record.
我是不想殺你的
I do not want to kill you.
但如果真有那個必要  我也不會心軟
But I absolutely will if I have to.
克雷·維裡斯都告訴你關於我的什麼了
What did Clay Verris tell you about me?
好  那我來跟你講講他吧
Okay, let me tell you about him.
因為我很瞭解維裡斯先生
Cause I know Mr. Verris very well.
他是怎麼開始訓練你的
How did he start you?
打鳥  射兔子嗎
Hunting birds, rabbit?
在你12歲左右時  他開始讓你打鹿
About 12 years old, he moved you up to deer.
接著我猜應該是在你19或20歲那會兒
I'm guessing 19 or 20 years old,
他第一次讓你去殺人了
the first time he ordered you to shoot a person.
我剛剛說的那些都是對的吧
Any of these ring a true?
是啊
Yeah.
他還告訴你要直面你的恐懼
He told you to lean into your fear.
因為你是個戰士
Because you were a warrior.
天生就註定有能力打敗弱小
Blessed with great gifts to defend the weak.
但他永遠都阻止不了你心裡的那個聲音
But he couldn't stop the noise.
你心底裡總有一塊疙瘩
That secret part of you that always felt
你就是和其他人有點不一樣
a little different than everybody else.
讓你覺得自己是個怪人
Part that felt like a weirdo.
你什麼都不知道
You don't know shit.
小子  我對你瞭若指掌
Kid, I know your inside out and backwards.
你對蜜蜂過敏  討厭香菜
You allergic to bees, you hate cilantro.
打噴嚏總是一連打4個
You always sneeze 4 times.
沒人喜歡吃香菜
Everybody hates cilantro.
你一絲不苟  嚴謹  威嚴  無情
You're meticulous, thorough, disciplined, relentless.
你還熱衷於解謎
You love puzzles.
你會下棋  對吧
You are a chess player, right?
而且  我賭你下得還不賴
Good too, I bet.
但你一直被失眠所折磨著
But you suffer from insomnia,
你的大腦不允許你入睡
your mind never lets you sleep.
就算有時你能入睡  也會被噩夢糾纏
And even when it does, it attacks you with nightmares.
我指的是那種你從淩晨三點做的那種
I am talking about those 3 o'clock in the morning -
"誰來救救我"的絕望噩夢
"somebody please save me" kind of nightmares.
這時候你就開始懷疑了
And then there's the doubts.
而懷疑從來不會有好結果
And those are the worst.
你很討厭它們  更討厭擁有它們的自己
You hate them, and you hate yourself for having them.
這讓你覺得自己很軟弱
They make you feel weak.
真正的士兵才不會處心積慮  不是嗎
A real soldier doesn't doubt, right?
唯一能讓你感到真正的快樂的時候
The only time you ever trully feel happy
是當你趴在地上準備扣下扳機的那一瞬間
is when you're flat on your belly about to squeeze the trigger.
在那一刹那  整個世界都完整了
And at that moment, the world makes perfect sense.
你覺得我是怎麼知道這些事情的
How do you think I know all of that?
你怎麼知道的關我屁事
I don't give a shit how you know anything.
看著我  蠢貨
Look at me, dummy!
看看我們
Look at us!
25年前  你父親提取了我的血並克隆了我
25 years ago, your father took my blood and he cloned me.
而後  他創造了你
He made you
從我這兒創造出來的
from me.
我們的基因一模一樣
Our DNA is identical.
他說的都是真相
He's telling you the truth.
閉嘴
Shut up!
他選了我  是因為從來沒人能到我這種境界
He chose me cause there's never been anybody like me,
而他深知  終有一天我會變老
and he knew one day I was gonna get old
而這就是你步入的時候了
and then you'd step in.
他一直在對你說謊
He's been lying to you the whole time.
他告訴你  說你是個孤兒
He told you you were an orphan.
而在整個世界這麼多人裡
And of all the people in the world to
他為什麼偏偏要送你來追我
come after me why would he send you?
因為我是最厲害的
Because I'm the best.
你很明顯不是最厲害的
You are obviously not the best.
你就是塊硬骨頭
You're a hard ass hit.
這本來應該是你的重生之日什麼的吧
Guess this was supposed to be your birthday or something that.
我必須得死  還必須得死在你的手裡
I had to die, and you had to do it.
只要我還活著
As long as I was alive somehow,
克雷的那個小實驗就永遠不是完美的
Clay's little experiment was incomplete.
你就是在為這樣的一個瘋子在扣扳機
That's the maniac you're pulling the trigger for.
閉上你的狗嘴
Shut your mouth about him!
你只是想打擊我而已
You just trying to rattle me.
我是想救你
I'm trying to save you!
你多大了  23歲吧
What are you, 23?
還是個處吧
Still a virgin, right?
是啊
Yeah.
苦苦地想要找個伴侶與之深入交流
Dying to be in a relationship and connect,
卻又唯恐有人和你走太近
but terrified to let anybody near you.
要是有人發現了真實的你怎麼辦
Because what if somebody actually saw who you are?
那他們還怎麼可能會愛你
How could they love you?
所以  大家在你眼裡都變成了一個個活靶子
So, everybody is just targets.
而你則是一把冷酷無情的武器
And you're just a weapon.
別對他開槍
Don't shoot him!
別打他
Don't shoot him
不  不要
No! Don't!
放下
Drop it!
放下  不然我就斃了你
Drop it! I will shoot you!
你不會的
No, you won't.
把他放開
Take your hands off of him!
放開他
Let him go!
馬上
Right now!
我不是你
I'm not you!
聽到了沒  老頭
You hear me, old man?
我不是你
I'm not you!
-他在哪裡  -他已經走了
- Where is he? - He's gone.
-擊中他了嗎  -應該是的
- Did you hit him? - I think so, yeah.
-傷到哪裡  -應該是肩膀
- Where? - Shoulder, I think.
那他會痊癒的
Then he'll recover.
那是好事嗎
Is that a good thing?
要知道
You know,
不是每天都有這樣的機會
It's not every day you see a guy
能看到一個人在兩個大洲被他自己
get his ass kicked on 2 continents.
打得落花流水
By himself.
去哪裡
Where to?
佐治亞州
Georgia.
維裡斯在的地方
Is where Verris is.
天哪
Man.
那個可憐孩子
That poor kid.
他一定被嚇壞了
He must be terrified.
他回家時一定感覺心如刀割
Then he's going home, walking into a buzz saw.
我稍微睡會兒  你也睡吧
I gonna get some sleep, you too.
睡不著  夢裡都是鬼魂
Not me, that's where the ghosts are.
睡吧
Sleep.
回答我
Tell me something.
為什麼要你殺他這麼難
Why is it so hard for you to kill this man?
你知道我有多討厭大吊床公園嗎  爸爸？
You know how much I hate Big Hammock Park, pop?
什麼
What?
從我12歲開始
Ever since I was about 12 years old.
每到生日  我們就去那裡打火雞慶祝
We were to shoot turkeys there for my birthday.
我一直都不喜歡
And I always hated it.
但我難道不是孤兒嗎
But I was an orphan, right?
那你是怎麼知道
So, how would we
我出生在哪天
even know when my Birthday was?
但你從未察覺到  所以我們每年都如此
But you never seen me notice so we just keep going.
好的  那你明年生日
Okay, so...
我們去吃查克芝士 [親子餐廳]
Next year we'll try Chuck E. Cheese.
好啊
Yeah.
那你  我
You, me
還有實驗室裡那幫
and the lab guys,
製造我的人一起
who made me.
好
Yeah.
我
I...
一直覺得
Always believed
你不知道的話能快樂點
you'd be happier not knowing.
快樂
Happy?
你知道我什麼時候覺得快樂嗎  爸爸
You know when I'm happy, pop?
當我伏在地上
When I'm flat on my belly,
準備扣動扳機的那一刻
about to squeeze the trigger.
這是我唯一覺得快樂的時候
It's the only time I'm happy.
這整件事甚至都不是意外
And this wasn't even a mistake.
不是你搞大了誰的肚子
It's not like you got someone pregnant
不得不擔負起責任撫養我
and then had to man up and raise me.
不  是你
No, you...
做了個決定
made a decision.
要讓一群科學家用一個人當範本
To have a scientist make a person
製造令一個人
out of another person.
不  事情不是這樣的
No, that's not what it was.
事情就是這樣的
That's exactly what it was.
然後你派我
Then you sent me
去殺他
to kill him.
世界上那麼多槍手  為什麼偏偏派我
Of all the shooters in the world, why would you send me?
這是你的夢魘  你需要自己經歷這一切
It's your darkness, you had to walk through this on your own.
或許你才是我的夢魘
Maybe you're my darkness.
你騙我說
That lie you told me.
我的父母
That my parents
把我丟棄在消防站
dumped me at a fire station.
我信了你的話
And I believed that.
你知道這話讓我多難過嗎
Do you know how that made me feel?
這是個必要的謊言
It was a necessary lie.
這一切都不是必要的
None of this shit is necessary!
是你選擇了要對我做這一切
You made a choice to do this to me.
-你難道看不出我現在有多"好"嗎  -放屁
- Can't you see how not okay I am? - Bullshit!
別忘了你是在和誰說話  小克
You forget who you are talking to, Junior.
我經歷過戰爭
I've seen battle.
看過戰士們崩潰于
I've seen soldiers go over the edge because
無法勝任的重擔
more was being asked of them than they can give.
但你不一樣
That's not you.
你的世界穩固可靠
Your world is stable and dependable.
是我確保的這一切
I made sure of that.
你擁有亨利從來沒有過的
You have something that Henry himself never had.
你有一個慈愛  無私  盡職的父親
You have a loving, dedicated, present father.
他他媽每天都告訴你
Who tells you every goddamnit day that
你很珍貴你很重要
you are precious and that you matter.
上帝啊  我做這一切的目的
Jesus, the whole point of this thing.
就是讓你不用經歷亨利的痛苦
Was to give you all of Henry's gifts
就能擁有他的天賦  我做到了
without his pain, and I did.
不要懷疑  小克
Don't doubt, Junior.
你能做得更好
You're better than that.
過來
Come here.
我愛你  兒子
I love you, son.
不要讓自己失望
Just don't let yourself down.
這次邂逅一如既往  短暫卻甜蜜
Like so many of my encounters, it was short, but sweet.
謝了  寶貝
Thanks, baby.
這附近應該有輛卡車
It should be truck here somewhere.
不許動
Don't move.
裡面是什麼
What was in that?
蜂毒
Bee venom.
你不能那麼做
You can't do that.
你不能那麼做  他對蜂毒過敏
You can't do that, he's allergic.
亨利  你能呼吸嗎
Henry, can you breathe?
亨利  努力呼吸
Henry, try to breathe.
-你還好嗎  -求你了
- You okay? - Please.
亨利  亨利  你能呼吸嗎
Henry, Henry, can you breathe?
求求你了
Please!
努力呼吸  亨利  亨利
Try to breathe, Henry. Henry!
呼吸
Breathe!
-你為什麼要這麼做  -拜託
- Why are you doing this? - Come on!
亨利  亨利  呼吸
Henry, Henry, breathe!
拜託
Come on!
亨利  呼吸
Breathe, Henry.
腎上腺素抗組胺藥 [抗過敏]
Epinephrine antihistamine.
你會沒事的
You'll be fine.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我只是想確認
I had to be sure.
不  沒事
No, it's all good.
這件事大家都很難接受
This whole shit's been a little difficult.
我不忍心打斷你們  但是
I hate to break up the party, but
你他媽怎麼總知道我們在哪
how the hell do you always know where we are?
他們在追蹤你
They're tracking you.
你相信我嗎
Do you trust me?
三年前的手術中給你裝的晶片
They chipped you. During your surgery 3 years ago.
維裡斯
Verris.
你也認識他
You know him too?
一起去過巴拿馬  科威特  索馬里
Panama, Kuwait, Somalia.
你能帶我們去找他嗎
Can you take us to him?
我們得阻止他
We need to shut him down.
我們兩個一起
Both of us.
你在費城長大對吧
You grew up in Philadelphia, right?
是的
Yeah.
叫波頓的一個地方
The place called the Bottom.
波頓
The Bottom.
跟我說說母親的事情
Tell me about my mother.
海倫·傑克遜·布洛根
Helen Jackson Brogan.
兩份工作幹了四十年
Worked two jobs for 40 years.
那女人以前經常抽我屁股
That woman used to whip my ass.
是不是你活該
Did you deserve it?
大多數時候
Usually.
我那時憤怒  愚蠢  從未真正
Does being angry and stupid
嘗試過任何事情  是不是活該
and never really trying at anything mean you deserve it?
父親不常在家  在我5歲時離開了
Our father wasn't around much, he left when I was 5.
我想母親每次都會在我臉上看見父親
And I think every time she looked at me, she just saw him.
我必須離開那裡
I had to get the hell outta there.
參了軍
Joined the Core.
我第一次交到了真正的朋友
First time I've ever made any real friends.
烏拉
'Oorah!'
在那認識了克雷·維裡斯
Met Clay Verris there.
發現了我非常非常擅長的東西
Found something I was really, really good at.
我離開的時候  胸前掛著獎章
By the time I left, I had medals on the chest.
母親已經去世了  然後
She was gone, and...
我就成了這幅樣子
I have become this.
你得在深陷泥潭前就離開那裡
You gotta walk away while you still can.
-我只會這些  -不  是他只教了你這些
- This is all I know. - No, this is all he taught you.
停手吧  你還來得及過另外一種生活
Stop now, you can still become something else.
當然了
Sure.
醫生還是律師
A Doctor? Lawyer?
丈夫  父親
Husband, father.
所有因為這份工作無法去做的事
And all the things this job gives you the excuse not to be.
我都未曾經歷過
I threw all of that away.
第二次機會再浪費掉實在可惜
It's shame to waste these gifts the second time around.
抱歉  還沒問過你名字
I'm sorry, what is your name?
他們一直叫我小克
It's always been Junior.
小克雷
Clay Junior.
我也不知道我該叫什麼了
I don't really know anymore.
這又是一個金盆洗手的好理由
That's another really good reason to quit.
你確定要去嗎
Do you sure about this?
我要和他談談
I need to talk to him.
我們見到他時怎麼做
So, what happens when we get to him?
他不會投降的
He's not gonna surrender.
他的電話
That's him.
我能跟他說話嗎
Can I talk to him?
我想第一個告訴他我們成為好朋友了
I want to be the one to tell him we all BFFs now.
接吧
Take it.
我是小克
This is Junior.
你和布洛根在一起嗎
Are you with Brogan?
我為什麼會和他在一起
Why would I be with him?
你派我去殺他的  不記得了嗎
You sent me to kill him, didn't you?
不重要了  快跑
It doesn't matter, just run.
什麼
What?
跑  離他遠點  快
Run, get away from him. Now.
小克  我只希望你安全無恙
Junior, I just want you safe.
為什麼
Why?
因為我是你最愛的實驗品嗎
Because I'm your favorite experiment?
不  因為我是你父親你必須聽我的
No, because I'm your father and you need to listen to me.
跑
Run!
下車  快跑
Get out off the car! Go!
巴倫
Baron!
不
No!
快走
Come on!
我很遺憾  亨利
I'm sorry, Henry.
-蜜雪兒警長  -請講
- Chief Mitchell? - Go ahead.
我是克雷·維裡斯  我希望你的小隊撤退
Clay Verris, I need your units to stand down.
長官
Sir?
我們正在與一個有生化武器的
We're engaging with a terrorist cell that
恐怖組織交火
has a weaponized biological capability.
所有小隊  馬上後撤  快
All units, go back, immediately!
聯邦當局已接到通知  正在來的路上
Federal authorities have been notified and they en route.
收到  有消息隨時通知  克雷
Affirmative, keep me posting, Clay.
是  長官
Yes, sir.
你現在得讓你的人撤退  快
You gotta stand your men down, now!
你做了正確的選擇  小克
You did the right thing, Junior
離開他
of walking away from him.
我這是懦夫之舉
I did what a coward would do.
令我自己噁心
Makes me sick!
是我對你要求的太多了
I was asking too much of you.
我現在明白了
I can see that now.
他不應該在車裡被導彈射死  父親
He deserves better than a missile shot into his car, pop.
他應該怎樣都無所謂  他非死不可
It doesn't matter what he deserves, he has to die.
你會命令那些暴徒們停手嗎
Are you gonna call those goons off now?
不會  但你可以
No. But you can.
開槍射死我  你來下命令
Just fire that. Take command.
盔甲的弱點在關節處
Armor's weak at the joints.
眼睛和脖子是致命點
Eyes and neck are the kill shots.
你右邊  我處理左邊
Take right, I'll take left.
槍口朝下
Muscle, discipline.
注意子彈數量
Watch you round count.
你掩護  我命中
You set, I spike.
-準備好了嗎  -明白
- Ready? - Roger that.
-我出來了  -找掩體
- I'm out! - Take cover!
去吧
Set!
趴下
Get down!
我是想讓你成為一個男子漢
I am trying to make you a man!
我應該克隆我自己的
I should have cloned myself.
慈愛  無私  盡職的父親
Loving, dedicated, present father?
就在那
Right there!
來吧
Go ahead.
動手吧
Do it.
你還有幾發子彈
How many rounds you got left?
一發
One.
好吧
Okay.
真抱歉
I'm sorry.
為什麼
For what?
把你牽扯進來
For getting you into this.
是我一直在監視你
I was the one surveilling you.
沒錯
Yeah.
不管怎麼說  抱歉
Anyway, sorry.
現在我們一起殺出去吧
Now let's fight our way out of this thing.
你是個好搭檔
You're a great partner.
謝謝你
Thank you.
對不起丟下你跑了
Sorry I ran.
沒關係  今晚確實很艱辛
Yeah, that's been a rough night.
外面還有多少人
How many more out there?
我沒看到還有
I didn't see any.
維裡斯呢
Verris?
不省人事了
Out of commission.
但還活著嗎
But still alive?
是
Yes.
拿著
Here.
傷口嚴重嗎
How bad is that?
我沒事
I'm fine.
你有事
You're not.
去守住電梯
Hold the elevator position.
我們去斷後
We gonna secure an out.
退後
Back off!
你不疼嗎
Don't you feel pain?
我不懂你為什麼這麼生氣  亨利
I don't know why you're so angry, Henry?
你是這一切的靈感來源
You were the inspiration for all of this.
你知道我是怎麼想的這個主意的嗎
You know where I got the idea?
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
在海夫吉
Khafji.
看到你在戰場上的風采
Watching you go house to house,
我不禁希望我手下有這樣一群人
wishing I had a whole division of men -
都和你一樣出色
all as good as you.
想著是否有這個可能
Wondering if that could be possible.
你應該感到受寵若驚
You should be flattered.
你該去死
You should be dead.
你看到這發生的一切了
You saw what happened over there.
一場暴行
An atrocities.
朋友的骨灰被送回家鄉
Friends being sent home in a pine box.
如果有更好的方法
Why should we accept that
為什麼我們要接受這一切
If there is a better way?
看看我們創造的一切
And look what we created.
他是你和我的合體
It's got both of us in.
你難道不認為你的國家
Don't you think your country deserves
值得擁有一個完美版本的你嗎
a perfect version of you?
從來都沒有完美版本的我
There is no perfect version of me,
或他  或任何人
or him, or anybody.
沒有嗎
No?
他本來要去葉門的
He was on his way to Yemen.
現在多虧了你
Now thanks to you
他的位置要被某個父母健在的人取代
his place is gonna be taken by someone with parents.
能感覺到疼痛
Someone who feels pain.
和恐懼
Fear.
那些我們在他身上剔除了的情感
Which we had edited out of him.
一個有諸多弱點的人
Someone with just as many weaknesses,
正如我們想要除掉的恐怖分子一樣
as the terrorists that we're trying to kill.
你覺得那樣更好嗎
And you gonna tell me that's better?
那你怎麼不把他們組建支軍隊
So why not make a whole army of 'em?
是啊  為什麼不呢
Yeah, why not?
想想看我們能拯救多少美國家庭
Think how many American families we can spare.
再沒有人的兒子  或女兒會戰死
Nobody's son, or daughter would ever have to die.
再也沒有老兵回家後患上創傷後應激障礙
No vet comes home with PTSD
然後自殺
and kills himself.
我們可以保障世界的安全
We can keep the whole world safe
不再有悲痛  所以
without any actual grief, so...
我傷害誰了嗎
Who would I be hurting?
你在講的可是人  克雷
You're talking about people, Clay.
亨利
Henry.
這是雙子實驗室做過最人性化的事了
This is the most humane thing that Gemini's ever done.
外面世界還有多少個我
How many more of me are running around out there?
只有一個你  小克
There's only one you, Junior.
他就是個武器
He was a weapon.
而你是我兒子
You're my son.
我愛你
And I love you.
就像任何父親愛任何孩子一樣
As much as any father ever loved any kid.
我沒有父親
I don't have a father.
永別了  克雷
Goodbye, Clay.
等等  等等
Hey, hey.
所以我們應該怎麼辦
So what the hell are we gonna do?
把他交出去嗎  他們不會審判他的
Gonna turn him in? They not gonna try him.
他們不會關掉他的實驗室的
They not gonna shot down his lab.
我們必須現在結束這一切
We have to end this this right now.
等等
Hey.
看著我
Look at me.
如果你按下了扳機
You pull that trigger
你就會毀掉你內心的一部分
and you gonna break something inside of yourself.
那部分再也不會癒合了
That will never get fixed again.
別這樣
Don't.
放手吧
Let it go.
把槍給我
Give it to me.
被鬼魂困擾的滋味可不好受
You don't want those ghosts.
相信我
Trust me.
你應該知道不該那樣做
You should know better than that.
真令人驚訝你竟然在乎這個
Surprised you give a shit.
既然這樣
Well...
我們做不成朋友了
We can't be friends anymore.
因為你的確讓他們殺我
Because you did let them try to kill me.
但這不代表我要眼看著你喝酒喝死
But, that doesn't mean I wanna see you drink yourself to death.
雙子實驗室被拆除了
The Gemini lab's been dismantled.
克隆項目已成歷史了
Cloning program is history.
那小克呢
And Junior?
沒人動得了他
He's untouchable.
沒人會去煩他了  再也不會了
No one will bother him. Ever.
而且我們調查過了  再沒有克隆人了
And we checked, there are no more clones.
那你有什麼打算
What about you?
監察主任打電話了
IG called.
我在等著起訴  但是
I'm looking at charges, but
如果我出庭指證珍內特
if I bury Janet,
可以爭取脫罪
I can make a deal.
她自找的
She earned it.
我真的很抱歉  亨利
I'm really sorry, Henry.
-保重  戴爾  -你也是
- Take care, Dell. - Yeah, you too.
退休快樂
And happy retirement.
六個月後
見到你真高興
Good to see you.
祝賀你升職了
Congrats on a promotion.
我聽說他們要搞點大計畫
I heard they got big plans.
不過經歷過你的事以後
Well, after you pretty sure
我覺得我什麼都應付得來了
I can handle anything.
-你最近怎麼樣  -還好  就是
- How've you been? - Good, just...
處理了巴倫的後事
Settled Baron's estate.
把他的骨灰撒到了加勒比海
Scattered his ashes in the Caribbean.
我也不知道  也許我現在想做的
I don't know, all I wanna do now is
就是為世界做些好事
put some good in the world.
但需要弄明白怎麼去做
Just gotta figure out how.
你會弄明白的
Yeah, you will.
你睡得還好嗎
You sleeping okay?
好多了
Better.
不再夢見鬼魂了
No ghosts?
不像之前那麼頻繁了
Not like before.
對了  前幾天我真的照了鏡子
Oh, and I actually looked in the mirror the other day.
-是嗎  -一點都不恐怖
- Really? - It wasn't horrendous.
說到照鏡子
Speaking mirrors.
一會見
Catch you later.
這是什麼
What's this?
這就是你
This is you.
護照  出生證明  駕照
Passport, birth certificate, driver's license.
顯然你信用度很不錯
Apparently you got pretty good credit.
我喜歡你選的名字
I love the name you chose.
傑克遜嗎
Jackson?
是我母親的名字
It's my mother's name.
她先是我的母親
She was my mother first.
好吧好吧
Yeah, yeah.
別跟我來敷衍這一套  小夥子
Don't you "yeah, yeah" me, young man.
走吧  我知道個吃午飯的好地方
Come on, I know a good place for lunch.
你選定專業了嗎
So you settled down on major yet?
傾向於選工程
Leaning towards engineering.
工程嗎
Engineering?
你應該聽她的
Yeah, you should listen to her.
如果我是你  我也確實算是
If I were you, which I sorta am,
我就選電腦科學
I'd go with computer science.
那個留著研究生再學
Save that for grad school.
應該先從人文學開始的
You want start with humanities.
-好吧別聽她的  -別聽他的
- Okay, don't listen to her. - Don't listen to him.
先學經典打好基礎
You need a grounding on the classics.
不好意思  我正和我自己說話呢
Excuse me, I'm trying to talk to myself over here.
你確實在自言自語  但你沒和他說話
Yeah, you are talking to yourself, but you're not talking to him.
聽著  我只是想趁年輕多犯錯
Look, I just made a lot of mistakes when I was young.
而且我真的想自己經歷錯誤
And I'd actually like to make some of those mistakes myself.
我想說的是我已經經歷過那些錯誤了
What I'm trying to say is, I made
所以你不必再經歷
them already so you don't have to.
但他不是你
But he's not you.
你們倆都冷靜一下
Okay, everybody chill the hell out.
我會沒事的
I'm gonna be okay.
如果你沒事
If you're okay,
那我就沒事
I'm okay.
怎麼了
What?
我就是不敢相信三十年後我會長成你這樣
I just can't believe that in 30 years I'm gonna look like you.
什麼  得了吧  你想得美
What? Please. You wish.
小子  你巴不得三十年後長得像我呢
Boy, you better hope you look like me in 30 years.
你面前的可是五十歲  成熟的老鮮肉
This is 50-year old, mature man meat you're looking at.
五十一歲
51.
我刷牙  我用牙線  我努力工作
I brush, I floss. I work hard.
等你五十歲了  我打賭你不能像我一樣
When you're 50, I bet you won't be
每天早上都爬起來跑步鍛煉
dragging your ass around the track every morning like I do.
事實上  我們可以現在就比一下
In fact, we can race now.
我們現在就比  現在就去那個拐角
We can race right now, we take it to the corner right now.
導演
李安